Guide to the Frank Altschul Papers,
Rare Book and Manuscript Library Columbia University Libraries
- Series V: Printed Materials, 1909-1984
  - The Merrymount Press, 1941, 1944 (Box 106, Folder 4)
  - Museum of Modern Art, 1941-1942 (Box 106, Folder 5)
  - National Committee for a Free Europe
    - General, 1953 (Box 106, Folder 6)
    - Transmission Routes--Maps, undated (Box 201 Oversize, Folder 1)
  - National Economic Council, 1944-1969 (Box 106, Folder 7)
  - National Health Council, 1949 (Box 106, Folder 8)
  - National Renaissance Party, 1953-1963 (Box 106, Folder 9)
  - National States Rights Party, 1964 (Box 106, Folder 10)
  - Neo Nazis: Great Britain, 1962 (Box 106, Folder 11)
  - Neo Nazi: Iceland, 1963 (Box 106, Folder 12)
  - Neo Nazi: Mexico, 1949-1956 (2 Folders) (Box 106, Folder 13 to 14)
  - Nixon, Richard, undated (Box 107, Folder 1)
  - Non Sectarian Anti-Nazi League, 1939-1951 (Box 107, Folder 2)
  - Palestine Arab Delegation, 1964 (Box 107, Folder 3)
  - Payroll Guarantee Association, undated (Box 107, Folder 4)
  - Pelley, William Dudley, 1941-1965 (Box 107, Folder 5)
  - Pelley-Pearson, Adelaide, 1944 (Box 107, Folder 6)
  - Pioneer News Service, undated (Box 107, Folder 7)
  - The Politics of Woodrow Wilson--Proof, undated (Box 107, Folder 8)
  - Popham, William Lee, 1944 (Box 107, Folder 9)
  - Porter, Paul, 1957 (Box 107, Folder 10)
  - Proskauer, Judge Joseph M., undated (Box 107, Folder 11)
  - Republican Party, 1964-1973 (Box 107, Folder 12)
  - Roosevelt, Eleanor, undated (Box 107, Folder 13)
  - Roosevelt, Franklin Delano, undated (Box 107, Folder 14)
  - Rusk, Dean, undated (Box 107, Folder 15)
  - Schlesinger, Arthur J., undated (Box 107, Folder 16)
  - Seligman, Eustace, 1976 (Box 107, Folder 17)
  - Seymour, Charles, 1951 (Box 107, Folder 18)
  - Slawson, John, 1955 (Box 107, Folder 19)
  - Social Justice, undated (Box 107, Folder 20)
  - Society for the Prevention of World War III, 1947-1950 (Box 107, Folder 21)
  - Spahr, Walter, 1943 (Box 107, Folder 22)
  - Stevenson, Adlai, 1973 (Box 107, Folder 23)
  - Straus, Nathan 3rd, undated (Box 107, Folder 24)
  - Tetens, T.H., 1955 (Box 108, Folder 1)
  - Toynbee, Arnold J., 1949 (Box 108, Folder 2)
  - Truman, Harry S., undated (Box 108, Folder 3)
  - U.S. Government Publications, 1942-1971 (2 Folders) (Box 108, Folder 4 to 5)
  - U.S. National Student Association, 1959 (Box 108, Folder 6)
  - U.S. Nationalist Party, 1964 (Box 108, Folder 7)
  - Valentine, Alan H., 1949-1951 (Box 108, Folder 8)
  - Vietnam, 1962-1967 (3 Folders) (Box 108, Folder 9 to 10)
  - Viner, Jacob, 1944-1950 (Box 108, Folder 11)
  - Vyshinsky, A.Y., undated (Box 108, Folder 12)
  - W.R.U.L. World Broadcasting, 1961 (Box 109, Folder 1)
  - Warburg, James P., 1957-1963 (4 Folders) (Box 109, Folder 2 to 5)
  - Ward, Barbara, 1948-1973 (2 Folders) (Box 109, Folder 6 to 7)
  - Warren, Earl, 1964 (Box 109, Folder 8)
  - White, Sentinel, 1955-1960 (2 Folders) (Box 109, Folder 9 to 10)
  - Williams, Robert H., 1951-1953 (Box 110, Folder 1)
  - Willkie, Wendell, 1940 (Box 110, Folder 2)
  - Wilson, Charles E., 1951 (Box 110, Folder 3)
  - Windrod, Gerald B., 1936 (Box 110, Folder 4)
  - Women's Voice, 1958 (Box 110, Folder 5)
  - Woodcut Society, 1945 (Box 110, Folder 6)
  - Zionist Organization of America, 1957-1972 (Box 110, Folder 7)
  - Clippings Collection--Sample, 1950s, (5 Folders) (Box 200)
- Series VI: Photographs, circa 1920-1960
  This series holds photographs of Frank Altschul, his wife Helen, and his parents Charles and Camilla Altschul. It also contains images of Altschul's estate, Overbrook Farm, in Stamford, Connecticut, the Altschul Auditorium at Columbia University, and buildings at the New School for Social Research, which Altschul helped fund.
  - Altschul, Charles, "The American Revolution in our School Text-Books," 1929 (Box 110, Folder 8)
  - Altschul, Charles and Camilla, undated (Box 110, Folder 9)
  - Altschul, Charles and Camilla--Early Residences, undated (Box 201 Oversize, Folder 7)
  - Altschul, Frank, undated (Box 110, Folder 10)
  - Altschul, Frank--Portrait, undated (Box 110, Folder 11)
  - Altschul, Frank--Portrait Sketch, undated (Box 201 Oversize, Folder 8)
  - Altschul, Frank and Helen--Early Residences, undated (Box 110, Folder 12)
  - Altschul, Frank and Helen--Library, undated (Box 110, Folder 13)
  - Altschul Auditorium, School of International Affairs, Columbia University, undated (Box 110, Folder 14)
  - Cordier, Andrew and Mrs., undated (Box 110, Folder 15)
  - "Joy of the Waters" Statue, 1945 (Box 110, Folder 16)
  - National Committee for a Free Europe, 1950s (Box 110, Folder 17)
  - New School for Social Research, undated (Box 110, Folder 18)
  - Overbrook Farm, 1929 (Box 110, Folder 19)
  - General, undated (Box 110, Folder 20)
- Series VII: Memorabilia, 1914-1916
  This small series contains Altschul's attorney certificates.
  - Goodhart, Arthur Lehman--Certificate, 1916 (Box 110, Folder 23)
  - Goodhart, Arthur Lehman--Attorney Certificates, 1914-1916 (Box 201 Oversize, Folder 3)
- Series VIII: Organizations, 1908-1980
  This series documents Altschul's involvement in social clubs and advocacy groups, including the American Jewish Committee, the Council for Foreign Relations, the National Committee for a Free Europe, and various committees at Yale University, among many others. Files for the Council for Foreign Relations are particularly extensive, containing correspondence, administrative records, budget information, and discussion notes and minutes from the organization's study groups. Files are arranged alphabetically by organization name and further organized by topic or document type.
  - American Foreign Service Association, 1967-1969 (Box 110, Folder 25)
  - American Friends Service Committee, 1949-1971 (Box 110, Folder 26)
  - American Institute of Graphic Arts, 1928-1930 (Box 110, Folder 27)
  - American Jewish Committee, 1945-1962, (2 Folders) (Box 110, Folder 28 to 29)
  - American Jewish Committee, 1964-1969, (5 Folders) (Box 111, Folder 1 to 5)
  - American Jewish Committee, 1970-1976, (7 Folders) (Box 112, Folder 1 to 7)
  - American Jewish Committee Commentary, 1964-1967 (Box 113, Folder 1)
  - American Schools of Oriental Research, 1942-1945 (Box 113, Folder 2)
  - Aspen Institute for Humanistic Studies, 1971 (Box 113, Folder 3)
  - Atlantic Council, 1973 (Box 113, Folder 4)
  - Atlantic Council, 1977-1979 (Box 114, Folder 1)
  - Atlantic Institute, 1960-1973 (Box 114, Folder 2)
  - Barnard College, 1965-1967 (Box 114, Folder 3)
  - Bates College, 1953-1973 (Box 114, Folder 4)
  - Book Clubs
    - Amateurs du Livre D' Art Francais, Les, 1947 (Box 115, Folder 1)
    - Amis Bibliophiles, Les, 1966 (Box 115, Folder 2)
    - Biographical Society, 1930-1931 (Box 115, Folder 3)
    - Companie de Bibliophiles du Livre D' Art & l' Amerigue Latine, 1966-1968 (Box 115, Folder 4)
    - Compagnie Typographie, 1931-1979 (2 Folders) (Box 115, Folder 5 to 6)
    - Grolier Club, 1966-1976 (Box 115, Folder 7)
    - Livre Contemporain et Les Bibliophiles Franco Suisse, Le, 1966-1968 (Box 115, Folder 8)
    - Noveau Cercle Parisien du Livre, 1966-1978 (Box 115, Folder 9)
    - General, 1949-1968 (Box 115, Folder 10)
  - Carrie Chapman Catt Memorial Fund, 1955-1958 (Box 115, Folder 11)
  - Center for Inter-American Relations, 1975 (Box 115, Folder 12)
  - Central Information Bureau, 1950 (Box 116, Folder 1)
  - Citizen's Committee For Reciprocal World Trade, 1948 (Box 116, Folder 2)
  - Citizens for Victory, 1941-1942 (Box 116, Folder 3)
  - Clubs
    - Century Association, 1958-1980 (Box 116, Folder 4)
    - Cosmopolitan Club, 1967,1980 (Box 116, Folder 5)
    - Cosmopolitan Club, 1966-1979 (Box 116, Folder 6)
    - Fifth Avenue Club, 1961-1974 (Box 116, Folder 7)
    - Gaslight Club, 1958, 1968 (Box 116, Folder 8)
    - Lotus Club, 1945-1979 (Box 116, Folder 9)
    - Metropolitan Club, 1967-1980 (Box 116, Folder 10)
    - Midtown Club, 1954-1979 (Box 116, Folder 11)
    - National Arts Club, 1924-1970 (Box 116, Folder 12)
    - Raffles, 1968-1974 (Box 116, Folder 13)
    - Stanwich Club, 1963-1978 (2 Folders) (Box 117, Folder 1 to 2)
    - Union Interalliee, 1967-1974 (Box 117, Folder 3)
    - Wall Street Club, 1961-1962 (Box 117, Folder 4)
    - General, A-Z, 1935-1971 (Box 117, Folder 5)
  - Colby College--Colby Speech, 1956 (Box 117, Folder 6)
  - Columbia University Correspondence, 1966-1975 (2 Folders) (Box 117, Folder 7 to 8)
  - Columbia University General and Libraries, 1952-1956 (Box 117, Folder 9)
  - Columbia University Graphic Art Center, 1952-1959 (Box 118, Folder 1)
  - Columbia University Lehman Suite and Library, 1966-1974 (Box 118, Folder 2)
  - Columbia University School of International Affairs, 1961-1976 (3 Folders) (Box 118, Folder 3 to 5)
  - Committee for Economic Development, 1978-1979 (2 Folders) (Box 118, Folder 6 to 7)
  - Committee for National Morale
    - Correspondence, 1940-1942 (3 Folders) (Box 118, Folder 8 to 9)
    - Memoranda, Clippings and General, 1940-1942 (2 Folders) (Box 119, Folder 1 to 2)
  - Committee for the Promotion of Advanced Slavic Cultural Studies, 1948-1965 (6 Folders) (Box 119, Folder 3 to 8)
  - Committee on the Present Danger--Correspondence and Reports, 1950-1954 (2 Folders) (Box 119, Folder 9 to 10)
  - Committee on the Present Danger--Reports and Printed Items, 1951-1954 (2 Folders) (Box 120, Folder 1 to 2)
  - Committee to Defend America by Aiding the Allies, 1941 (Box 120, Folder 3)
  - Common Council for American Unity, 1953 (Box 120, Folder 4)
  - Connecticut State Library, 1959 (Box 120, Folder 5)
  - Council for Democracy, 1948 (Box 120, Folder 6)
  - Council for Middle Eastern Affairs, 1956 (Box 120, Folder 7)
  - Council for Foreign Affairs--General Correspondence 1921-1947 (2 Folders) (Box 120, Folder 8 to 9)
  - Council for Foreign Affairs--General Correspondence, 1948-1973 (Box 121-127)
  - Council for Foreign Affairs
    - General Correspondence, 1974-1980, (7 Folders) (Box 128, Folder 1 to 7)
    - Administrative Files--Annual Reports, 1958 (Folder 8)
      - Annual Reports, 1962-1969, (8 Folders) (Box 129, Folder 1 to 8)
      - Board of Directors, 1962-1963 (2 Folders) (Box 129, Folder 9 to 10)
      - Board of Directors
        - 1964-1973 (9 Folders) (Box 130, Folder 1 to 9)
        - Harry Boardman's Memo, 1969 (Box 131, Folder 1)
        - Bundy Correspondence, 1971 (Box 131, Folder 2)
        - Davis Resolution, 1955 (Box 131, Folder 3)
        - Letters of Recommendation and Acknowledgement, 1972 (Box 131, Folder 4)
        - Meetings, 1955-1973 (7 Folders) (Box 131, Folder 5 to 11)
      - Budget, 1953-1955 (2 Folders) (Box 131, Folder 12 to 13)
      - Budget, 1958-1973 (4 Folders) (Box 132, Folder 1 to 4)
      - By-Laws, 1959 (Box 132, Folder 5)
      - Candidates for Membership, 1952-1976 (6 Folders) (Box 132, Folder 6 to 11)
      - Committee on Membership, 1952-1957, (3 Folders) (Box 132, Folder 12 to 14)
      - Committee on Membership, 1958-1972 (8 Folders) (Box 133, Folder 1 to 8)
      - Committee on Selections, 1963 (Folder 9)
        - General, 1957-1958 (Box 133, Folder 10)
        - 1959-1972 (7 Folders) (Box 134, Folder 1 to 7)
        - Meetings, 1971 (3 Folders) (Box 134, Folder 8 to 10)
        - Meetings, 1972 (2 Folders) (Box 135, Folder 1 to 2)
        - Staff Minutes, 1965 (Box 135, Folder 3)
      - Conference on Leaders of World Affairs, 1953 (Box 135, Folder 4)
      - Elihu Root Lectures, 1968-1969 (Box 135, Folder 5)
      - Finance
        - General, 1952-1954 (3 Folders) (Box 135, Folder 6 to 8)
        - Chase National Bank, 1954 (Box 135, Folder 9)
        - New York Trust Company, 1954 (Box 135, Folder 10)
        - General, 1955 (Box 135, Folder 11)
        - General, 1957-1964 (8 Folders) (Box 136, Folder 1 to 8)
        - Carnegie Corporation Funding Proposal, 1964 (Box 137, Folder 1)
        - General, 1965 (Box 137, Folder 2)
        - Capital Fund Program, 1965 (2 Folders) (Box 137, Folder 3 to 4)
        - General, 1966-1968 (2 Folders) (Box 137, Folder 5 to 6)
      - Ford Foundation Grant--Proposal, undated (Box 137, Folder 7)
      - Ford Project--China, 1962-1964 (3 Folders) (Box 138, Folder 1 to 3)
      - Foreign Affairs, 1968-1969 (Box 138, Folder 4)
      - Forkosch Memo and Response, 1971 (Box 138, Folder 5)
      - Fundraising Campaigns, 1952-1959 (8 Folders) (Box 139, Folder 1 to 8)
      - Fundraising Campaigns, 1960-1967 (8 Folders) (Box 140, Folder 1 to 8)
      - Harriman, Averill W.--Meeting, 1959 September 14 (Box 140, Folder 9)
      - Malik, Charles--Presentation, 1957 (Box 140, Folder 10)
      - New Building, 1954-1955 (Box 140, Folder 11)
      - Nobel Institute Conference and Report, 1945-1955 (Box 140, Folder 12)
      - Reports, 1969 (Box 141, Folder 1)
      - Retirement Fund, 1953 (Box 141, Folder 2)
      - Staff Meeting Minutes, 1963 (Box 141, Folder 3)
      - Studies on Foreign Policy, 1965-1968 (3 Folders) (Box 141, Folder 4 to 6)
      - Studies Program--American Dilemma in Vietnam, 1965-1966 (Box 141, Folder 7)
      - Tax Exempt Status, 1953 (Box 141, Folder 8)
      - 25th Anniversary Fund, 1946-1947 (Box 141, Folder 9)
      - The United States in World Affairs, 1954 (Box 141, Folder 10)
    - Discussion and Study Groups
      - Arms Limitation and Control--Director's Policy Group, 1960 (Box 141, Folder 11)
      - Asian and American Policies--Study Group, 1969 (Box 141, Folder 12)
      - Atlantic Alliance Group, 1970 ( 2 Folders) (Box 141, Folder 13 to 14)
      - Atlantic Policy Study Groups
        - Atlantic Policies and Institutions--Drafts of Proposal, 1962 (Box 142, Folder 1)
        - Correspondence, 1962-1964 (2 Folders) (Box 142, Folder 2 to 3)
        - General, 1963 (4 Folders) (Box 142, Folder 4 to 7)
        - General, 1964-1966 (5 Folders) (Box 143, Folder 1 to 5)
        - Committee on Studies, 1963-1964 (2 Folders) (Box 143, Folder 6 to 7)
        - Hudson Institute Report, 1964 (2 Folders) (Box 144, Folder 1 to 2)
        - Morgenthau Study, 1965 (Box 144, Folder 3)
        - Reflections on the April 28-29 Conference, 1964 (Box 144, Folder 4)
      - British Image in America--Study Group, 1960 (Box 144, Folder 5)
      - China--Study Group, 1958 (2 Folders) (Box 144, Folder 6 to 7)
      - Communist China and U.S. Policy in Asia--Study Group, 1959 (Box 144, Folder 8)
      - East-West Economic Relations--Discussion Group, 1969 (Box 144, Folder 9)
      - East-West Economic Relations--Discussion Group, 1967 (Box 145, Folder 1)
      - Eastern Europe--Discussion Group on U.S. Policy Toward East Central Europe, 1950-1957 (3 Folders) (Box 145, Folder 2 to 3)
      - Economic Policy--Discussion Group on Study Group, 1949-1950 (Box 145, Folder 4)
      - Economic Policy--Study Group on U.S. Foreign, 1956-1957 (3 Folders) (Box 145, Folder 5 to 6)
      - Economic Policy--Study Group on U.S. Foreign, 1959 (Box 146, Folder 1)
      - Foreign Policy--Study Group, 1960-1961 (2 Folders) (Box 146, Folder 2 to 3)
      - Foreign Policy--Ad Hoc Study Group on U.S., 1966 (Box 146, Folder 4)
      - Foreign Policy--Study Group on the Re-examination of America, 1959 (Box 146, Folder 5)
      - German Foreign Policy--Study Group on American Interest, 1964 (Box 146, Folder 6)
      - Germany--Study Group, 1957 (Box 146, Folder 7)
      - Germany's Position in Western Europe--Study Group, 1954 (Box 146, Folder 8)
      - Germany's Position in Western Europe--Study Group, 1955 (Box 147, Folder 1)
      - Gross, Ernest, The United Nations: Structure for Peace--Correspondence, 1962 (Box 147, Folder 2)
      - Guerilla Warfare, Discussion Group on the Political Aspects of Unconventional Warfare, 1961 (Box 147, Folder 3)
      - Herter, Chris, Toward an Atlantic Community--Correspondence, 1963 (Box 147, Folder 4)
      - Intelligence and Foreign Policy--Discussion Group, 1967 (Box 147, Folder 5)
      - International Political Communication--Study Group, 1963 (Box 147, Folder 6)
      - "International Trade: The Search for Patterns"--Corporation Service Seminar for Business Executives, 1964 (Box 148, Folder 1)
      - Israel, Dinner Seminar on Domestic Developments, 1968 (Box 148, Folder 2)
      - Mason, Ed--Notes, 1963 (Box 148, Folder 3)
      - Middle East, Discussion Group on the Role of the Military, 1963 (Box 148, Folder 4)
      - Middle East, Discussion Group on U.S./Soviet Relations, 1971 (Box 148, Folder 5)
      - Study Group on the Defense of the Middle East, 1955-1956 (3 Folders) (Box 148, Folder 6 to 8)
      - Middle East--Study Group on U.S. Policy, 1969 (Box 148, Folder 9 to 10)
      - N.A.T.O.--Study Group, 1962 (Box 149, Folder 1)
      - Non-Nuclear Force in a Nuclear Age--Discussion Group, 1968 (4 Folders) (Box 149, Folder 2 to 5)
      - Nuclear Weapons and U.S. Foreign Policy--Study Group, 1954-1955 (5 Folders) (Box 149, Folder 6 to 10)
      - Political and Strategically Problems of Deterrence--Study Group, 1958 (3 Folders) (Box 149, Folder 11 to 13)
      - Political and Strategically Problems of Deterrence--Study Group, 1959-1960 (2 Folders) (Box 150, Folder 1 to 2)
      - Political Role of the Military Force--Discussion Group, 1970-1972 (9 Folders) (Box 150, Folder 3 to 11)
      - Population Problems and Foreign Policy--Discussion Group, 1962 (Box 150, Folder 12)
      - Power and Policy--Study Group, 1963 (Box 150, Folder 13)
      - Power and Policy--Study Group, 1963 (Box 151, Folder 1)
      - Report to the Senate Foreign Relations Committee, Ad Hoc Group, 1959 (2 Folders) (Box 151, Folder 2 to 3)
      - Russia--Study Group on U.S. Relations, 1946-1958 (Box 151, Folder 4)
      - Russia and the West: Summary for the Corporation Service Seminar for Business Executives, 1963 (Box 151, Folder 5)
      - Soviet-American Relations--Study Group, 1955 (Box 151, Folder 6)
      - Soviet-American Relations--Study Group--Correspondence, 1952-1957 (Box 151, Folder 7)
      - Soviet-American Relations--Study Group--Correspondence, 1955 (2 Folders) (Box 152, Folder 1 to 2)
      - Soviet Foreign Economic Policy--Discussion Group, 1956-1957 (2 Folders) (Box 152, Folder 3 to 4)
      - Strategic Bases and Alliances--Discussion Group, 1958 (Box 152, Folder 5)
      - Strategy and Foreign Policy--Study Group, 1960 (Box 152, Folder 6)
      - United Nations and US. Foreign Policy--Discussion Group, 1957-1959 (Box 153, Folder 1)
      - U.S. Information Activities Abroad--Ad Hoc Meeting, 1960 (Box 153, Folder 2)
      - U.S. Shipping Policy, 1957 (Box 153, Folder 3)
      - Vietnam--Ad Hoc Study Group, 1968 (Box 153, Folder 4)
      - Vietnam, Discussion Group on the Post-Conflict Prospects, 1967 (Box 153, Folder 5)
      - Yugoslavia and Eastern Europe, Study Group, 1958-1959 (2 Folders) (Box 153, Folder 6 to 7)
  - Council On World Tensions, Inc., 1964-1965 (Box 153, Folder 8)
  - Declaration of Atlantic Unity--Correspondence 1959-1965 (Box 153, Folder 9)
  - Declaration of Atlantic Unity, Correspondence, 1966-1972 (Box 154, Folder 1)
  - Deerfield Academy, 1935-1947 (Box 154, Folder 2)
  - Democratic National Committee, 1945-1949 (Box 154, Folder 3)
  - Democratic Party, 1970-1976 (Box 154, Folder 4)
  - Dublin Conference, New Hampshire, 1945-1968 (2 Folders) (Box 154, Folder 5 to 6)
  - East European Fund, 1951-1965 (Box 154, Folder 7)
  - Empire State Foundation, Helen G. Altschul, 1955-1956 (Box 154, Folder 8)
  - English Speaking Union
    - Correspondence, 1963-1974 (3 Folders) (Box 154, Folder 9 to 11)
    - Correspondence, 1975-1980 (4 Folders) (Box 155, Folder 1 to 4)
    - Warburg, Paul Felix, 1965 (Box 155, Folder 5)
    - Winston Churchill Memorial Fund, 1965-1967 (2 Folders) (Box 155, Folder 6)
  - Europe-American Conference at Amsterdam, The Netherlands (Box 155)
  - Ferguson Library, 1955-1974 (Box 156, Folder 1)
  - Fight For Freedom, undated (Box 156, Folder 2)
  - Fire Companies Building Corporation, 1938 (Box 156, Folder 3)
  - First American Fire Insurance Company, 1939 (Box 156, Folder 4)
  - First Panel, Sheriff's Jury, 1928-1929 (Box 156, Folder 5)
  - Foreign Policy Association, 1957-1979 (3 Folders) (Box 156, Folder 6 to 8)
  - Foreign Service Educational Foundation, 1960-1964 (Box 156, Folder 9)
  - France-America Society, 1959-1973 (Box 156, Folder 10)
  - Free Russia Fund, 1951 (2 Folders) (Box 156, Folder 11 to 12)
  - Freedom House, 1941-1973 (2 Folders) (Box 156, Folder 13 to 14)
  - Friends of Democracy, 1940-1944 (2 Folders) (Box 157, Folder 1 to 2)
  - Fund for Peace, 1971-1974 (Box 157, Folder 3)
  - Girl's and Boy's Service League, 1964-1974 (Box 157, Folder 4)
  - Girl's Club of America, Inc., 1965-1966 (Box 157, Folder 5)
  - Hudson Institute, 1962-1969 (4 Folders) (Box 157, Folder 6 to 9)
  - Hudson Institute, 1970-1978 (4 Folders) (Box 158, Folder 1 to 4)
  - Institute for World Order, Inc. Correspondence with Douglas Dillon, 1975 (Box 158, Folder 5)
  - Institute for International Education, 1961-1979 (Box 158, Folder 6)
  - Institute on Man and Science, 1966-1976 (3 Folders) (Box 158, Folder 7 to 9)
  - Institute on Man and Science, 1971-1973 (Box 159, Folder 1)
  - League of Women Voters, New York and Stamford, Connecticut, 1953-1976 (2 Folders) (Box 159, Folder 2 to 3)
  - Memberships, Organizations, Clubs, 1950-1974 (3 Folders) (Box 159, Folder 4 to 6)
  - Mianus River Valley, Correspondence, 1966-1967 (2 Folders) (Box 160, Folder 1 to 2)
  - General Organizations, 1951-1976 (Box 160, Folder 3)
  - Morgan Library, 1954-1979 (Box 160, Folder 4)
  - National Book Committee, 1955-1974 (Box 160, Folder 5)
  - National Citizen's Commission on International Cooperation, 1964-1966 (Box 160, Folder 6)
  - National Committee for a Free Europe
    - Executive Committee Meetings, 1949-1950 (Box 161, Folder 1)
    - General, 1949-1950 (5 Folders) (Box 161, Folder 2 to 6)
    - General Files, 1949-1952 (6 Folders (Box 161, Folder 7 to 12)
    - General Files 1953-1976, (7 Folders) (Box 162, Folder 1 to 7)
    - Addresses of Staff Members, 1950-1951 (Box 163, Folder 1)
    - Balloon Operations, 1954-1956 (Box 163, Folder 2)
    - Board Meetings, 1950-1951 (Box 163, Folder 3)
    - Budget, 1950-1951 (Box 163, Folder 4)
    - Campaign Executive Committee, 1950 (Box 163, Folder 5)
    - Certificate of Incorporation and Personnel Information, 1951 (Box 163, Folder 6)
    - Crusade for Freedom, 1951-1952 (Box 163, Folder 7)
    - Free Russia Fund, 1951 (Box 163, Folder 8)
    - Free University in Exile, 1953 (Box 163, Folder 9)
    - Istanbul Project, undated (Box 163, Folder 10)
    - Mid-European Study Center Reports, 1951 (Box 163, Folder 11)
    - Mid-European Study Center Reports, 1952 (Box 164, Folder 1)
    - National Committee, Treasurer, 1951 (Box 164, Folder 2)
    - Notes from the Foreign language Press, 1951 (Box 164, Folder 3)
    - Peroutha, Ferdinand, 1951 (Box 164, Folder 4)
    - Policy Guidelines
      - General, 1951-1953 (Box 164, Folder 5)
      - Bulgaria, 1951 (Box 164, Folder 6)
      - Czechoslovakia, 1951-1953 (Box 164, Folder 7)
      - East Germany, 1950 (Box 164, Folder 8)
      - Hungary, 1951 (Box 164, Folder 9)
      - Poland, 1950-1953 (Box 164, Folder 10)
      - Romania, 1951 (Box 164, Folder 11)
    - Publications and Pamphlets, 1949-1953 (Box 164, Folder 12)
  - National Committee for a Free Europe--Radio Free Europe
    - German Poster, undated (Box 202 Scroll, Folder 1)
    - General (5 Folders) (Box 165, Folder 1 to 5)
    - "A" File, 1950 (Box 165, Folder 6)
    - Altschul, Frank
      - Correspondence, 1950-1951 (Box 165, Folder 7)
      - Dinner Guest Lists, 1950-1951 (Box 165, Folder 8)
      - Montclair Speech, 1950 (Box 165, Folder 9)
      - Notes, 1950 (Box 165, Folder 10)
      - Scripts, 1951 (Box 165, Folder 11)
      - Untitled Speech, undated (Box 165, Folder 12)
      - Veterans of Foreign Wars Speech, 1951 (Box 165, Folder 13)